A Finding Aid to the Louis Pomerantz Papers, 1937-1988, bulk 1950s-1988, in the Archives of American Art aaa.pomeloui
Archives of American Art
- Project/Client Files, 1950s-1987; Series 5; 13.8 Linear feet Boxes 7-20 (Box 7, Folder 9-12)
  - Miwaukee Art Center/Museum, 1950s-1960s (Box 15, Folder 25-26)
  - Milwaukee Art Center/Museum, 1950s-1970s (Box 15, Folder 27-30)
  - Milwaukee Art Center/Museum, 1960s-1980s (Box 15, Folder 31-40)
  - Milwaukee Art Center/Museum, 1980s (Box 15, Folder 41-45)
  - Milwaukee Art Museum, Conservation Grant, 1980s (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Milwaukee Art Center, Examination Reports, 1950s-1980s (Box 16, Folder 2-4)
  - Milwaukee Art Center/Museum, Layton Collection Examination Reports, 1960s (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Milwaukee Art Center/Museum, Priority #1, October 11, 1963 List, 1950s-1960s (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Miwaukee Art Museum/Center Surveys, 1974-1983 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Milwaukee Auction Galleries, 1970s-1980s (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Milwaukee Private Collectors, 1960s-1970s (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Milwaukee Public Library, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 10-11)
  - Minnesota Historical Society, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 12-14)
  - Miscellaneous Examination Reports, 1970s-1980s (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous/Unidentified, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 16, Folder 16-17)
  - Monroe, Margaret, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Moore, Mrs. H., 1970s (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Morris, George L. K., 1950s (Box 16, Folder 20-21)
  - Morris, Nelson, 1960s (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Morton, Steve L., 1969-1979 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Mosley, Dr. M., 1980s (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Murdock Collection, 1950s-1960s (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Murdock Collection Examination Report, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1950s-1980s (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - National Gallery of Canada, Ottowa, 1960s (Box 16, Folder 28-29)
  - National Woman's Christian Temperance Union, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Nebenzahl, Kenneth, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Nelson, Barbara L. Garrett, 1960s-1980s (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Nelson, Elenore von Kern, 1980s (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Nevins, Robert, 1980s (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Neuberger, Roy R., circa 1950s (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Newberry Library, 1960s-1970s (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Newbury, Michael, 1960s (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Newman, Mrs. Albert H., 1950s-1980s (Box 16, Folder 38-39)
  - Newman, Robert J., 1959 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Nicholson, Mrs. James, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Norris, Dellora and Lester, 1950s-1960s (Box 16, Folder 42-43)
  - Norris, Dellora and Lester, 1960s-1970s (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - North American Van Lines, Inc. and Thomas F. Healey, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - North Shore Country Club, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Northern Illinois University, 1970s-1980s (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Northern Trust Company (Marianne Lohan, Mies Van der Rohe Estate), 1950s-1970s (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Norton Simon Foundation, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - O'Brien Galleries, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Oehlschaeger Galleries, 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Ohio Historical Society, 1970s-1980s (Box 17, Folder 8-10)
  - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1970s-1980s (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Olsen-New & Associates, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Omaha Metropolitan Arts Council, 1970s-1980s (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Oppenheimer, Mrs. Edward, 1970s-1980s (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Orlando, Frank, 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Ortlieb, David W., 1980s (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Oshkosh Pubic Museum, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Ott, Wendel Fentress, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Ottawa, Silica Company, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Pabst Brewing Company, 1960s-1970s (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Paepcke, Mrs. Walter, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Paley, Arnold and Madeleine, 1975-1980 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Pallas, Mickey, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Palmer, Gordon, 1959-1960 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Park Ridge Historical Society, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Pasadena Art Museum, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Patterson, Mrs. Arthur C., 1950s (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Patterson, Elizabeth A., 1960s-1970s (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Peter, William F., 1960s-1970s (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Philbrook, F. H., 1950s-1970s (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Phillips, Rhoda, 1969-1974 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Phylis Kind Gallery, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Pick, Albert, 1950s-1970s (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Pick, Grant J. and Mrs. Frederic, 1950s-1960s (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Pierre Matisse Gallery, 1950s (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Plain, George L., 1969-1970 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Plainford Public Library, 1950s-1960s (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Poedtke, Carl H., Jr., 1983 (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Powell, Mrs., circa 1950s (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Prince, Mrs. William Wood, 1950s-1960s (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Prinzloff, Elinor G., 1971 (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - Prifzker, Mrs. A. N., 1969 (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - Pritzker, Jay, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - R. R. Donnelley & Sons Company, 1961-1978 (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - Radigan, Mr. and Mrs. William J., 1986 (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - Radov, Sylvia, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - Raffles, Richard, 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - Reis, Gordon, Jr., 1971 (Box 17, Folder 48)
  - Render, Henry, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 49)
  - Ricau, James, 1950s (Box 17, Folder 50-52)
  - Richard Feigen Gallery, 1964-1966 (Box 17, Folder 53)
  - Ripon College, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 54)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A., circa 1950s (Box 17, Folder 55)
  - Roloff, John, 1960s (Box 17, Folder 56)
  - Roth, Shirley, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 57)
  - Rubenstein, Mrs. Hehna, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 58)
  - Rugen, Carl E., 1955 (Box 17, Folder 59)
  - Sack, Suzanne, 1959-1960 (Box 17, Folder 60)
  - Saffron, Dr., 1956 (Box 17, Folder 61)
  - Saks, Mrs. Julien, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 62)
  - San Francisco Museum of Art, 1960s (Box 17, Folder 63-64)
  - San Francisco Museum of Modern Art, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 65)
  - San Fratello, Japer M., 1970s (Box 17, Folder 66)
  - Sang, Philip D., 1960s-1970s (Box 17, Folder 67)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 68)
  - Schneckloth, Helen, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 69)
  - Schooler, Lee, 1960s (Box 17, Folder 70)
  - Schraeger, Al (Victorian Shop), 1950s-1960s (Box 17, Folder 71)
  - Schulman, Bernice F., 1971 (Box 17, Folder 72)
  - Schulman, Jerome and Joan, 1970s (Box 17, Folder 73)
  - Schulze, Franze, 1960s-1970s (Box 17, Folder 74)
  - Schwahn, Nancy & W. W., 1970s (Box 17, Folder 75)
  - Sears Vincent Price Gallery, 1960s-1970s (Box 17, Folder 76)
  - Seckel, Helmut P. G., 1957-1958 (Box 17, Folder 77)
  - Seegers, Paul A. (GAB Business Services Inc.), 1970s (Box 17, Folder 78)
  - Seiberling, Frank A., 1970s (Box 17, Folder 79)
  - Shaffer, Van Vechten, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 80)
  - Shapiro, Joseph, 1950s-1960s (Box 17, Folder 81)
  - Shapiro, Joseph, 1970s (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Shelburne Museum, circa 1950s (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Smit, Mrs. J. J., circa 1950s (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Smith College Museum of Art, 1950s (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Smith, Edward Byron, 1960s (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Smith, Richard W., 1970s (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Smith, Solomon B., 1970s-1980s (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Smyth, Mrs. Nelson E., 1960s-1980s (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Smyth, Patricia Black, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Soby, James Thrall, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Soria, Martin, 1960s (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Sound Recording labeled "Resa/Argonne Lab/Corot Exhibit, circa 1960s; 1 sound tape reels (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - South Dakota State Historical Society, 1970s (Box 18, Folder 13-14)
  - Southern Illinois University, 1970s-1980s (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Spaeth, Otto L., 1954-1955 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Spencer, M. Lyle, 1960s (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Spertus, Maurice, circa 1979 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Squash Blossom Gallery, Inc., 1980s (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Stamler, Dr. Jeremiah, 1960s-1970 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Standard Rate and Data Service, Inc., 1980s (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - State Historical Society of Iowa, 1974-1975 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - State Historical Society of Wisconsin, 1970s (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Stemberg Galleries, 1970s (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Steur, W. R., 1981-1982 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Stevens Institute of Technology, circa 1950s (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Stewart, Lonnie, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Stone, Jerome, 1960s-1970s (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Stryker, Wm. B., 1955 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Tavern Club, 1983-1984 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Tedeschi, John A., 1960s (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Terra Museum of American Art, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 32-33)
  - Thayer, circa 1950s (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Theobald, William F., 1980s (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Tolman, Charles E., 1980s (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Toplis and Harding, Inc., 1950s-1970s (Box 18, Folder 37-38)
  - Tow, Ray and Susan, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Travelers Insurance Company, 1970s (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Trepagnier, Francis B., 1960s-1980s (Box 18, Folder 41-42)
  - Tripp, Chester D., 1950s-1960s (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - Troy, Carl E. and Minna, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - Uilein, Lorraine, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Union League Club of Chicago, 1970s (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - Unitarian Church of Evanston, 1960s-1980s; Includes 1 sound tape reel with program "Relgion Through the Arts, Order of Service, May 10, 1964" (Box 18, Folder 47-49)
  - United States Postal Service, 1970s-1980s (Box 19, Folder 1-4)
    Includes photos of Pomerantz at work on post office murals
  - University Club, Milwaukee, 1960s-1970s (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - University Club of Chicago, 1946-1980s (Box 19, Folder 6-7)
  - University of California, Los Angeles, 1980s (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - University of Chicago, 1970s (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - University of Chicago Law School, 1980s (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - University of Chicago, Oriental Institute, 1960s (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - University of Illinois, Department of Art, circa 1960 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - University of Iowa, Museum of Art, 1960s (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - University of Iowa, Museum of Art, 1960s-1970s (Box 19, Folder 14-17)
  - University of Iowa, Museum of Art, 1970s (Box 19, Folder 18-22)
  - University of Iowa, Museum of Art, 1970s-1980s (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - University of Iowa, Museum of Art, Photos of Pomerantz by Leslie B. Hartigan, 1960s-1970s (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - University of Missouri-Columbia, 1980s (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - University of Texas at Austin, 1960s (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee, 1960s-1980s (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Valparaiso University, 1980s (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1950s (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Vogel, Fred III, 1970s-1980s (Box 19, Folder 30-31)
  - Vondermuhl, Kate, 1950s (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Voorhees, Mrs. Clifford, 1950s (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Wabash College, 1960s (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Wainwright, Alice C., 1950s (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Walker Art Center, 1960s-1970s (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Walker, Maynard, 1950s (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Walter, Mr. and Mrs. Michael, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Walter P. Chrysler, Jr., Collection, 1950s (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Walton-Myers, Edith and James, 1980s (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
  - Watters, Dr. and Mrs., 1950s (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Weeks, Katherine W., 1953 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Weil, Corrine, 1980s (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Weiland, Bernard and Rae, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Weingberg and Weingberg, Ltd., 1970s (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Weingarten, Maxwell, 1970s (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Weinstein, Harold X., 1950s-1960s (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Weiss, David, 1970s (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Weiss, Edward H., 1960s-1970s (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Werner, Walter G., 1980s (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Westinghouse Electric Corporation, 1970s (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Wichita Art Museum Publications, 1960s-1970s (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Wichita Art Museum, Ronald P. Murdock Collection, 1960s-1980s (Box 20, Folder 15-20)
  - Wiedersum, F., circa 1950s (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Wight, Frederick (UCLA Council), 1960s (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Will, Lester J., 1960s (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Wittreich, Joseph, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Wolff, Art H., 1970 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Wood, Arthur M., 1950s-1970s (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Young, Henry J., 1970s (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Zeisler, Claire, 1960s-1980s (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Zeisler, Richard S., 1950s (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Zekman, Theodore N., 1970s (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Zurcher, Suzette, 1950-1960s (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Unfinished Work (Box 20)
    - Bennet, Harvey, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Dawson, Mrs. J. K., 1986 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Edwards, Mr. and Mrs. John, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - Gunde, Green, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Hynes, Nancy D., 1982-1987 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Imig, Ray, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - International Minerals and Chemical Corp., 1986-1987 (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - Lewis, John D. and Phoebe, 1983-1987 (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - McWilliams, James and Mary, 1986-1987 (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Mel, Bernard, 1986-1988 (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - Milwaukee Art Museum, 1985-1987 (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - Peterson, Michael, 1986-1987 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - Rotcheiler, Holga and Robert, 1986-1987 (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - Seiberling, Frank, 1984-1987 (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - Walker Art Center, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - Witt, Bob, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 47)
- Teaching and Reference Files, 1940s-1980s; Series 6; 3.9 Linear feet Boxes 20-24; Pomerantz, Louis
  Series is arranged as 2 subseries.
  6.1: Organizations and Events, 1940s-1980s
  6.2: Subject Files, 1940s-1980s
  This series documents Pomerantz's involvement with professional organizations and events, and houses subject files of reference material collected for professional development purposes.
  - Organizations and Events, 1940s-1980s; 6.1
    This series does not include Pomerantz's contributions at professional events, which can be found in Series 4: Writings and Notes, but does document his attendance and involvement in events such as AIC and International Institute for Conservation of Historical and Artistic Works annual meetings and other conferences primarily in the midwest and California. The records document some of the most prominent and pressing issues in art conservation during the 1960s-1980s.
    Records include committee material such as lists of meeting attendees, calls for papers, memoranda, correspondence and notes, conference handouts and other printed material, and 62 sound cassettes and 5 sound tape reels of conference presentations and events.
    - American Association for State and Local History, Seminar, 1970s (Box 20, Folder 48)
    - American Association of Museums, Annual Meeting, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - American Institute for Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works (Box 20)
      - Annual Meeting (1980), 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 50)
      - Cleaning Techniques, 1960s-1970s (Box 20, Folder 51)
      - "Guidelines for Selecting a Conservator", 1980s (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Panel on Mural Painting, 1970s-1980s (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Preprints of Papers, Dearborn, Michigan, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Proposed Papers, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Business Meetings and Conference Presentations, 1970s-1980s; 62 Sound cassettes (Box 21, Folder 5-13)
    - Business Meetings and Conference Presentations, 1970s-1980s (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
    - Fogg Art Museum, Center for Conservation and Technical Studies Conference, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Fogg Art Museum, Center for Conservation and Technical Studies Workshop Seminar, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Foundation of the American Institute for Conservation, Compensation of Losses, 1980s (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Foundation of the American Institute for Conservation, Wood Refresher Course, 1980s (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Illinois Agriculture and Textile Museum, 1966; 3 sound tape reels (Box 22, Folder 7-8)
    - Intermuseum Conservation Association, 1980s (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - International Dinner, circa 1960s; Includes 1 sound tape reel (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - International Institute for Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works, 1970s-1980s (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - International Institute for Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works, Abstracts, 1950s-1960s (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - International Institute for Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works, AAM Art Technical Section, 1961; 1 sound tape reels (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - International Institute for Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works, Damaged Test Strip Sample, 1960s (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - MidAmerica College Art Assocation Conference, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Midwest Museums Conference, 1960s-1970s (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Midwest Museums Conference, 1977-1981 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, Application of Science in Examination of Works of Art, Seminar, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - University of California Forest Products Laboratory, Wood in Art Conservation Seminar, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 19-20)
    - University of Minnesota, Collective Concerns Conference, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Upper Midwest Conservation Association, 1980s (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Subject Files, 1940s-1980s; 6.2
    Subject files include reference material gathered by Pomerantz on a wide range of conservation-related subjects. Found are printed material, correspondence, photographic material, and sound recordings on 2 sound tape reels.
    - Adhesives, circa 1970s (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Agreement and Release Form Samples, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Aluminum Supports (Carroll Wales), 1966 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Appraiser Certification Material, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Bibliographies, circa 1950s (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Cassandre Poster, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Causes of Damage to Art Objects, 1970s (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Chemistry of Art, 1980s (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Cibachrome Prints Processing, 1960s-1977 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Cleaning of Paintings, 1980s (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Color, 1970s (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Deacidification of Papers, 1970s (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Disaster Planning, 1970s-1980s (Box 23, Folder 9-10)
    - Easel Construction, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Equipment, 1950s-1960s (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Ethics Codes and Professional Standards, 1950s-1980s (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Examination Form Samples, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 23, Folder 14-16)
    - Exhaust Systems, 1980s (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Expert Opinion on Seurat's La Grande Jatte Varnish Question, 1950s (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Gainsborough Products Ltd., 1970s (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Gamelan Project Material Identification, 1970s-1980s (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - General Reference Material, 1960s-1980s (Box 23, Folder 21-23)
    - "Gore-Tex" Moisture Barrier Silica Tile, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Historic Preservation, 1970s-1980s (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Institute of Paper Chemistry, 1980s (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Insurance for Conservators, 1970s (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Lamp on Floor Stand, 1980s (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Lighting for Museums and Galleries, 1980s (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Lining Techniques, 1950s-1980s (Box 23, Folder 30-33)
    - M.T.I. Instrumentation Grade Video Systems (Alexander Katlan), 1980s (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Masonite Corporation, 1950s (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Negative Ions, 1980s (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Occupational Hazards, circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Paper Samples, 1950s-1960s (Box 23, Folder 38-39)
    - Photo Labs and Equipment, 1960s-1980s (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Pigments Dating Chart, circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Professional Papers, 1950s-1970s (Box 24, Folder 1-5)
    - Professional Papers by Walter C. McCrone, 1960s-1980s (Box 24, Folder 6-7)
    - Restoration, 1950s-1980s (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Salaries Civil Service, Grades, 1970s-1980s (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Security and Theft of Artwork, 1960s-1980s; Includes 2 sound tape reels (Box 24, Folder 10-14)
    - Smoke Deodorizers, circa 1980s (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Solvents, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Stereoradiography, 1960s-1970s (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Stretchers (Frame Designs and Orders), 1960s-1980s (Box 24, Folder 18-20)
      Includes correspondence regarding stretcher orders by Pomerantz
    - Stretchers (Munn, Ben-APF Manufacturing Inc. Framemakers), 1960s-1970s (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Textile Conservation Workshop, 1980s (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Transfer Methods (Jim Roth), 1958 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Vacuum Table for Paper Objects, 1970s (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - X-Ray, 1940s (Box 24, Folder 25)
- Personal Business Records, 1950s; Series 7; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 24-25
  Personal business records consist primarily of receipts for professional supplies from the 1950s in addition to one folder of business tax records.
  - Business Taxes, 1950s (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Receipts (Box 24)
    - Canvas Stretching Frames, Linen, 1952-1956 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Chemicals, 1952-1956 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Entertainment, 1950s (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Hardware, 1952-1956 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Insurance, 1955-1956 (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Lumber, 1952-1955 (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Misellaneous, 1950s (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Paintings Delivered and Received, 1950s (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Paper and Stationery, 1950s (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - Photography, 1950s (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Photography Supplies and Equipment, 1950s (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Supplies, 1950s (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Travel, 1950s (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Printed Material, 1937-1970s; Series 8; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 25, 33
  Printed material consists primarily of news clippings about Pomerantz, including a group intended for use in a scrapbook, as well as other conservation-related news clippings, blank postcards of artwork, and 2 exhibition catalogs for St. Julian Fishburne.
  - About Pomerantz, 1950s-1960s (Box 25, Folder 5-8)
  - About Pomerantz ("L. P. Scrapbook"), 1937-1970s (Box 25, Folder 9-11)
    Oversized material housed in Box 33, Folder 2
  - Clippings on Conservation, 1950s-1960s (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1960-1962 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Museum of Modern Art Fire, 1958 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Postcards of Artwork, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 25, Folder 15-17)
  - Oversized About Pomerantz ("L. P. Scrapbook") from Box 25, Folder 11 (Box 33, Folder 2)
- Photographic Material, 1940s-1980s; Series 9; 8.4 Linear feet Boxes 25-36, OV 37, MGP 1
  Minimal processing did not allow time for full arrangement of the photographic material and re-housing of the slides in this series. Where possible, Pomerantz's original groupings and labels were preserved and are reflected in the Container Listing. Some slides, including the bulk of the project/client slides, are unsorted, and include glass slides mounted in an unorthodox method devised by Pomerantz. Some, however, were removed to archival housing and existing labels were saved or transcribed where possible. Original groupings for otherwise unidentified slides are represented, where possible, by slide containers and dividers.
  Photographic material primarily documents conservation treatments and techniques through photographs, slides, negatives, glass slides, and 5 glass plate negatives. Many images show Pomerantz and others engaged in conservation work and artwork at various stages in the conservation process.
  Photographs of artists include Tessa Macintosh, Ulfert Wilke, and a signed photo of Georgia O'Keeffe.
  Photos of Pomerantz at work include 2 photos of him at the Winterthur Museum working with conservator Joyce Hill Stoner who was instrumental in organizing the Know What You See exhibition. Additional material showing Pomerantz at work can be found throughout the series.